<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Volume 01 - Interregnum on The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>/commentary/</link><description>Recent content in Volume 01 - Interregnum on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 20:20:41 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/commentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01.038 Analepsis</title><link>/commentary/01.038-analepsis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 20:20:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.038-analepsis/</guid><description>The Aqrabuamelu fight a lot</description></item><item><title>01.013 Sparring</title><link>/commentary/01.013-sparring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:55:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.013-sparring/</guid><description>Now you see the true power of Ella’s very mild enhanced healing. Since this is a rational, progression story with an entirely optional litrpg backbone, I wanted to have a bit of slice of life period showing that she is intensely following up on her action items. So this is part of the training montage for hand-to-hand.
Since I know about fighting than physics expect me to spend more time on those scenes rather than her studying.</description></item><item><title>01.012 Halloween</title><link>/commentary/01.012-halloween/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.012-halloween/</guid><description>A bit more training montage, but I wanted to bring back in some magic and even a sense of wonder. I feel like I missed the mark a bit. But that is okay.
I am not a hard magic guy for the most part despite some of my rpg type posts - my eyes glaze over at most hard magic systems, so I prefer it to be a bit ineffable.</description></item><item><title>01.011 Breathe</title><link>/commentary/01.011-breathe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:01:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.011-breathe/</guid><description>I was going for that calm before the storm vibe here, she is mentally getting her head into the game a bit. Taking stock. Taking time with her family.
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably come back and build this out when I do a big second pass to build on that feel more. But sometimes a chapter is just short.</description></item><item><title>01.010 Prep</title><link>/commentary/01.010-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:00:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.010-prep/</guid><description>Dealing with one&amp;rsquo;s parents is often something that is brushed over in fantasy. You can&amp;rsquo;t have adventures with watchful parents. I somewhat get around this by having my protagonist be older, in grad school. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean she is estranged from her family, just exasperated sometimes.
Her father being an actor once and now a professor and her mother being a physician is intentional. She comes from an educated background but not one that is solely that way.</description></item><item><title>01.009 Exposition</title><link>/commentary/01.009-exposition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 13:34:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.009-exposition/</guid><description>Who knew that dwarves were trolls? Sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself.
Obviously I wanted to subvert the trope a bit that dwarves were either fools like in LOTR or stoic. At the same time, I also added my own spin on them, making them rock-like creatures that are a bit more alien in nature than humans.
There is always a bit of give and take with that since you have to balance their alieness with their ability to interact in a meaningful way with humans.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude Kennington</title><link>/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>This chapter I am always going to say was super hard.
First, I was trying to write a character I can&amp;rsquo;t even say I pretend to understand, a council estates kid in Kennington, London from Brixton. So I am going to completely fuck up the vernacular and regional differences. He is teamed up with a native East Londoner from Kennington and a Brazilian Portuguese girl and they run into a couple Haitian lwa.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>/commentary/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.007-again/</guid><description>This chapter was more difficult to write than the others - lots of establishing new characters and trying to imply familial relationships but with a hopefully light touch. Maybe I crammed too many conversations in here and didn&amp;rsquo;t let each one breathe, but it is a trade-off between endless dialog and moving things along, and in this story, it was just a bit of a breather.
Next chapter will be radically different.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>This was all Ella needing to feel real, and I did not expect it when I wrote it. A lot of the time characters pull you along with their own actions, and you just let them.
She kind of skipped from denial to the end. Was it truly acceptance or was it her just going a bit more wild? I kind of thought of her as a third date kind of girl, but sometimes your own characters surprise you.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>/commentary/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>After the disappointment Ella experienced in her last chapter, I felt like I needed to kickstart the story with more evidence and someone else who maybe knows a little bit more than her. Most YA stories start with the parents dying so nobody can protect or explain what is going on - and the slow reveal is important to build this. But you can be slow, and you can be glacial.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>Ella is very good at denial but the cracks are showing. She puts back on the denial at the end but how much longer can it last.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>/commentary/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>I encourage you to channel some Sailor Moon magical girl sequencing here. Get your mind out of the gutter though - no semi-nude intermediate step.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>Yes it is a bit of a skip ahead, but often I find that the pacing of stories feels unrealistic. Also a month of having crystalline white eyes and putting in contacts to cover them makes it feel more real that she is back to living her life for the most part.
And then you get ambushed by a party. A magical dance party in Harlem on your way up town.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>/commentary/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.001-vision/</guid><description>Welcome When I started this story, I had a couple goals in mind.
A compelling character that struggles a bit with her identity, but is smart and capable; and also someone my children could see themselves as; To have flexibility in how the story progressed and the fantastical elements - to be able to switch genre freely; I wanted to have fun writing something; And although I hate litrpg in text, I wanted to track character development and abilities in a formal way using those stats rathre than having plot armor be the only driver; Other characters who behave in rational, adult ways, that have deep internal lives and motivations even if we don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are; and Finally I wanted to write a story for adults with adult themes and concerns.</description></item></channel></rss>