<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Volume 01 - Interregnum on The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>/commentary/</link><description>Recent content in Volume 01 - Interregnum on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:20:40 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/commentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01.136</title><link>/commentary/01.136/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:20:40 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.136/</guid><description/></item><item><title>01.128 Belong</title><link>/commentary/01.128/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:20:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.128/</guid><description/></item><item><title>01.129 Family</title><link>/commentary/01.129-family/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:20:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.129-family/</guid><description/></item><item><title>01.133 An Average Day</title><link>/commentary/01.133/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:20:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.133/</guid><description/></item><item><title>01.121 Astray</title><link>/commentary/01.121/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:20:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.121/</guid><description/></item><item><title>01.108</title><link>/commentary/01.108/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:19:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.108/</guid><description>Kothin knelt on the marble floor before his liege.
&amp;ldquo;The girl?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Badly injured but alive. The Aqrabuamelu are guarding her in New York.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;And your asset?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Disappeared. Djara may be dead.&amp;rdquo;
Ekerri sat back on his throne, idly playing with his scepter. The girl was turning into a real threat. She had suborned the Aqrabuamelu somehow. And, recently, had drawn so much magic from the crown it had dimmed slightly on his head.</description></item><item><title>01.106 Pickle</title><link>/commentary/01.106-pickle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:19:06 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.106-pickle/</guid><description>Ella is done camping</description></item><item><title>01.103 SNAFU</title><link>/commentary/01.103-snafu/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:19:01 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.103-snafu/</guid><description>Jade and Craig get a little too creative</description></item><item><title>01.098</title><link>/commentary/01.098/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 14:18:48 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.098/</guid><description>So some stories and investigations are short and end quickly.
I realize that Ella being stuck in the woods for a week might have a lot of people going, when the hell will magic become a major part of this story? So I thought Ella&amp;rsquo;s hunting week would be a good week to meet some of the other characters and see their perspectives.</description></item><item><title>01.044 Interlude - Apsáalooke</title><link>/commentary/01.044-interlude-apsaalooke/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 20:30:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.044-interlude-apsaalooke/</guid><description>This chapter starts as a standard western setup and I pivot it near the end to show that not all these spirits waking up are bad. They are not a horrors, but complicated and strange.
I apologize if I didn&amp;rsquo;t get the vibe right or if there is a bit of stereotyping going on. Wish I knew more native Americans to validate the depiction better. Watching interviews and researching just don&amp;rsquo;t get the right sensitivity.</description></item><item><title>01.072 Increments</title><link>/commentary/01.072wip-increments/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 20:30:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.072wip-increments/</guid><description>A little slice of life in the 0.1%. I love writing Charlie chapters but often think she is a bit predictable persona wise. That is okay&amp;hellip; but I would like to give her a bit more depth and nuance and maybe something a bit more, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t come to me yet. But she writes her own chapters and I originally thought this would go another way.
Her father is an asshole, no question.</description></item><item><title>01.081 Grace</title><link>/commentary/01.081-grace/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.081-grace/</guid><description>Ella has an idea</description></item><item><title>01.079 Bird and Wolf</title><link>/commentary/01.079-bird-and-wolf/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.079-bird-and-wolf/</guid><description>Ella jumps a cowboy</description></item><item><title>01.066 Poet</title><link>/commentary/01.066-poet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.066-poet/</guid><description>The High Priestess gets demoted</description></item><item><title>01.059 False Dischotomy</title><link>/commentary/01.059-false-dichotomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.059-false-dichotomy/</guid><description>The bug squad needs some healing</description></item><item><title>01.038 Analepsis</title><link>/commentary/01.038-analepsis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 20:20:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.038-analepsis/</guid><description>The Aqrabuamelu fight a lot</description></item><item><title>01.022</title><link>/commentary/01.022-coffee/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:55:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.022-coffee/</guid><description>This is where I think I will really lose any of the sticklers physicists since I clearly have no idea what I am talking about. So I ask for their forbearance and even dialogue around it.
This chapter was also way too much exposition and nothing much has happened for a few chapters. I am unsure how balance the peaks and valleys since this is a serial and I didn&amp;rsquo;t plot those all in advance.</description></item><item><title>01.021 - Reset</title><link>/commentary/01.021-reset/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:55:12 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.021-reset/</guid><description>Ella lay in bed. The sunlight peeked through the drawn curtains and denied her sleep. She was tired after staying up the whole night but her mind kept racing through what she had heard.
She pulled her phone out and started to write notes on it all. And seeing it in print left very few choices.
She typed on her phone quickly and then slowed down as the conclusion became inevitable:</description></item><item><title>01.020 - Quant</title><link>/commentary/01.020-history/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 13:26:29 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.020-history/</guid><description>I rewrote this chapter since the first version had too fast and predictable a resolution.</description></item><item><title>01.019 - Anxiety</title><link>/commentary/01.019-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 13:26:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.019-anxiety/</guid><description>A small reference to Archer, one for the Witcher, and another to Dune. Because why not? Ella is doing what she can while still being in school but she knows it isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. And how do you investigate a secret. That took me a while to figure out and in the end you need a lead.
And the paper I linked to, well it is about muons not measuring quite right and that is awesome stuff if you are trying to dig into the fundamentals of the universe.</description></item><item><title>01.018 - Farflung Interests</title><link>/commentary/01.018-farflung/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 13:26:23 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.018-farflung/</guid><description>Chile is just a lovely place. This story has to be global in nature as I mentioned before, and some of these folks we are going to see are going to have interests outside of the US. It is a US centric story, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean other countries don&amp;rsquo;t have things going on.
A lot of interludes and mini-stories will end up being one-offs of weirdness. Some may come back depending on how the story develops, so maybe instead of threads, they are seeds that may or may not sprout.</description></item><item><title>01.017 Aqrabuamelu</title><link>/commentary/01.017-aqrabuamelu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:19:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.017-aqrabuamelu/</guid><description>This is a remix of Mesopotamian myths where the Akkadians come from warrior fanatic scorpion men and, if you know your history, eventually supplant the Sumerians.
Hi there I Sorry Utu for casting you as the bad guy. No deities were harmed in the writing of this.</description></item><item><title>01.016 Blooded</title><link>/commentary/01.016-blooded/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:19:37 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.016-blooded/</guid><description>Ella needed a win for all the work she has been putting in. But wins shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too easy and I wonder if this one was. But it was a plot dictated issue in that if she staggers home with significant wounds, that is going to be hard to write off.
So let&amp;rsquo;s just say that ghula was a very, very weak one. If someone asks me about it, that is my story.</description></item><item><title>01.015 Investigation</title><link>/commentary/01.015-investigation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:19:17 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.015-investigation/</guid><description>Ella has access to resources most people wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, being a physics grad student. So why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t she go stick things in a Scanning Electron Microscope or use other gear. I made her overly nervous and she could have walked in and just asked to use it which is something I think a lot of people would feel.</description></item><item><title>01.014 Punked</title><link>/commentary/01.014-punked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:19:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.014-punked/</guid><description>Notice a common theme with Ella’s training? If you say getting knocked on her ass, you would be right.
Obviously training the way she does only takes you so far for real fighting. Add knives, bites, and friends to an MMA match and it will go south fast. I am not a knife fighter by any means and my understanding is the loser is basically who bleeds out first. May have to do more research there.</description></item><item><title>01.013 Sparring</title><link>/commentary/01.013-sparring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:55:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.013-sparring/</guid><description>Now you see the true power of Ella’s very mild enhanced healing. Since this is a rational, progression story with an entirely optional litrpg backbone, I wanted to have a bit of slice of life period showing that she is intensely following up on her action items. So this is part of the training montage for hand-to-hand.
Since I know about fighting than physics expect me to spend more time on those scenes rather than her studying.</description></item><item><title>01.012 Halloween</title><link>/commentary/01.012-halloween/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.012-halloween/</guid><description>A bit more training montage, but I wanted to bring back in some magic and even a sense of wonder. I feel like I missed the mark a bit. But that is okay.
I am not a hard magic guy for the most part despite some of my rpg type posts - my eyes glaze over at most hard magic systems, so I prefer it to be a bit ineffable.</description></item><item><title>01.011 Breathe</title><link>/commentary/01.011-breathe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:01:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.011-breathe/</guid><description>I was going for that calm before the storm vibe here, she is mentally getting her head into the game a bit. Taking stock. Taking time with her family.
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably come back and build this out when I do a big second pass to build on that feel more. But sometimes a chapter is just short.</description></item><item><title>01.010 Prep</title><link>/commentary/01.010-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:00:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.010-prep/</guid><description>Dealing with one&amp;rsquo;s parents is often something that is brushed over in fantasy. You can&amp;rsquo;t have adventures with watchful parents. I somewhat get around this by having my protagonist be older, in grad school. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean she is estranged from her family, just exasperated sometimes.
Her father being an actor once and now a professor and her mother being a physician is intentional. She comes from an educated background but not one that is solely that way.</description></item><item><title>01.009 Exposition</title><link>/commentary/01.009-exposition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 13:34:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.009-exposition/</guid><description>Who knew that dwarves were trolls? Sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself.
Obviously I wanted to subvert the trope a bit that dwarves were either fools like in LOTR or stoic. At the same time, I also added my own spin on them, making them rock-like creatures that are a bit more alien in nature than humans.
There is always a bit of give and take with that since you have to balance their alieness with their ability to interact in a meaningful way with humans.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude Kennington</title><link>/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>This chapter I am always going to say was super hard.
First, I was trying to write a character I can&amp;rsquo;t even say I pretend to understand, a council estates kid in Kennington, London from Brixton. So I am going to completely fuck up the vernacular and regional differences. He is teamed up with a native East Londoner from Kennington and a Brazilian Portuguese girl and they run into a couple Haitian lwa.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>/commentary/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.007-again/</guid><description>This chapter was more difficult to write than the others - lots of establishing new characters and trying to imply familial relationships but with a hopefully light touch. Maybe I crammed too many conversations in here and didn&amp;rsquo;t let each one breathe, but it is a trade-off between endless dialog and moving things along, and in this story, it was just a bit of a breather.
Next chapter will be radically different.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>This was all Ella needing to feel real, and I did not expect it when I wrote it. A lot of the time characters pull you along with their own actions, and you just let them.
She kind of skipped from denial to the end. Was it truly acceptance or was it her just going a bit more wild? I kind of thought of her as a third date kind of girl, but sometimes your own characters surprise you.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>/commentary/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>After the disappointment Ella experienced in her last chapter, I felt like I needed to kickstart the story with more evidence and someone else who maybe knows a little bit more than her. Most YA stories start with the parents dying so nobody can protect or explain what is going on - and the slow reveal is important to build this. But you can be slow, and you can be glacial.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>Ella is very good at denial but the cracks are showing. She puts back on the denial at the end but how much longer can it last.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>/commentary/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>I encourage you to channel some Sailor Moon magical girl sequencing here. Get your mind out of the gutter though - no semi-nude intermediate step.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>Yes it is a bit of a skip ahead, but often I find that the pacing of stories feels unrealistic. Also a month of having crystalline white eyes and putting in contacts to cover them makes it feel more real that she is back to living her life for the most part.
And then you get ambushed by a party. A magical dance party in Harlem on your way up town.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>/commentary/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.001-vision/</guid><description>Welcome When I started this story, I had a couple goals in mind.
A compelling character that struggles a bit with her identity, but is smart and capable; and also someone my children could see themselves as; To have flexibility in how the story progressed and the fantastical elements - to be able to switch genre freely; I wanted to have fun writing something; And although I hate litrpg in text, I wanted to track character development and abilities in a formal way using those stats rathre than having plot armor be the only driver; Other characters who behave in rational, adult ways, that have deep internal lives and motivations even if we don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are; and Finally I wanted to write a story for adults with adult themes and concerns.</description></item><item><title>01.082 Sin</title><link>/commentary/01.082-sin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.082-sin/</guid><description>Ella has an idea</description></item><item><title>01.082 Sin</title><link>/commentary/01.083-nascent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/commentary/01.083-nascent/</guid><description>Ella tries to own her sins</description></item></channel></rss>