<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Commentaries on The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/</link><description>Recent content in Commentaries on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="https://tknx.github.io/">Tarun Nagpal&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:19:33 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01.014 Punked</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.014-punked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:19:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.014-punked/</guid><description>Notice a common theme with Ella’s training? If you say getting knocked on her ass, you would be right.
Obviously training the way she does only takes you so far for real fighting. Add knives, bites, and friends to an MMA match and it will go south fast. I am not a knife fighter by any means and my understanding is the loser is basically who bleeds out first. May have to do more research there.</description></item><item><title>01.013 Sparring</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.013-sparring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:55:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.013-sparring/</guid><description>Now you see the true power of Ella’s very mild enhanced healing. Since this is a rational, progression story with an entirely optional litrpg backbone, I wanted to have a bit of slice of life period showing that she is intensely following up on her action items. So this is part of the training montage for hand-to-hand.
Since I know about fighting than physics expect me to spend more time on those scenes rather than her studying.</description></item><item><title>01.012 Halloween</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.012-halloween/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.012-halloween/</guid><description>A bit more training montage, but I wanted to bring back in some magic and even a sense of wonder. I feel like I missed the mark a bit. But that is okay.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude Kennington</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>This chapter I am always going to say was super hard.
First, I was trying to write a character I can&amp;rsquo;t even say I pretend to understand, a council estates kid in Kennington, London from Brixton. So I am going to completely fuck up the vernacular and regional differences. He is teamed up with a native East Londoner from Kennington and a Brazilian Portuguese girl and they run into a couple Haitian pretwo lwa.
Second, I wanted it to be very in media res, but given how fast things go south, I had to move a bunch of stuff up front.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.007-again/</guid><description>This chapter was more difficult to write than the others - lots of establishing new characters and trying to imply familial relationships but with a hopefully light touch. Maybe I crammed too many conversations in here and didn&amp;rsquo;t let each one breathe, but it is a trade-off between endless dialog and moving things along, and in this story, it was just a bit of a breather.
Next chapter will be radically different.
Also, Ella switching between her American name and Indian name is very intentional.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>This was all Ella needing to feel real, and I did not expect it when I wrote it. She kind of skipped from denial to the end. Was it truly acceptance or was it her just going a bit more wild? I kind of thought of her as a third date kind of girl, but sometimes your own characters surprise you.
And then, of course, she got stabbed.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>After the disappointment Ella experienced in her last chapter, I felt like I needed to kickstart the story with more evidence and someone else who maybe knows a little bit more than her. Most YA stories start with the parents dying so nobody can protect or explain what is going on - and the slow reveal is important to build this. But you can be slow, and you can be glacial.
So Jae-Young shows up. A guy who asked her out early on but they only got around to a date now.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>Ella is very good at denial but the cracks are showing. She puts back on the denial at the end but how much longer can it last.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>I encourage you to channel some Sailor Moon magical girl sequencing here. Get your mind out of the gutter though - no semi-nude intermediate step.
Footnotes are purely optional and just for fun. Being much older, I will have to work on making my music choices more age appropriate, but I figured an orc DJ can be any age.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>Yes it is a bit of a skip ahead, but often I find that the pacing of stories feels unrealistic. Also a month of having crystalline white eyes and putting in contacts to cover them makes it feel more real that she is back to living her life for the most part.
And then you get ambushed by a party. A magical dance party in Harlem on your way up town. Charlie doesn&amp;rsquo;t get past the red rope of magic.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.001-vision/</guid><description>A quick intro Well here we go&amp;hellip; I wanted to include some chapter by chapter commentary as I write these, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want unnecessary author&amp;rsquo;s notes, nor did I want them to be attached to the chapters directly. Think of this as the purely optional director&amp;rsquo;s track.
And, to be fair, I will spoil the chapters as I see fit, so read those first.
When I started this story, I had a couple goals in mind.</description></item></channel></rss>