<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/</link><description>Recent content on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="https://tknx.github.io/">Tarun Nagpal&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thethousandkingdoms.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>Yes it is a bit of a skip ahead, but often I find that the pacing of stories feels unrealistic. Also a month of having crystalline white eyes and putting in contacts to cover them makes it feel more real that she is back to living her life for the most part.
And then you get ambushed by a party. A magical dance party in Harlem on your way up town. Charlie doesn&amp;rsquo;t get past the red rope of magic.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>6 October 2021 - Harlem, New York City, United States “Why do I have to go uptown to study anyway? I know we are just going up there so you can flirt with your boyfriend.” Ella whined a bit on the A train as it pulled away from the station.
“Shut up… it isn’t that big of a deal and I like to get out of the Village sometimes for a change, you know. Plus it is Thursday night and we can go out afterwards.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.001-vision/</guid><description>A quick intro Well here we go&amp;hellip; I wanted to include some chapter by chapter commentary as I write these, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want unnecessary author&amp;rsquo;s notes, nor did I want them to be attached to the chapters directly. Think of this as the purely optional director&amp;rsquo;s track.
And, to be fair, I will spoil the chapters as I see fit, so read those first.
When I started this story, I had a couple goals in mind.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.001-vision/</guid><description>9 September 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States “Don’t go down there.”
Charlie looked over and smiled. “I hear there are secret tunnels and strange stuff. Let’s do this!”
She held up her phone showing a picture of something. It was hard to follow as her hand wasn’t steady and she was stumbling a bit anyway.
“They aren’t yellow bricks, but let’s go!” Charlie prompted that by climbing down off the platform, her short sparkly, clubbing dress riding up as she slide down the side</description></item><item><title>Dramatis Personae</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/dramatis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/dramatis/</guid><description>Humans Donna Arthurs-Kennedy - Ella&amp;rsquo;s sparring partner. Very tall at 177cm / 5'10&amp;quot; and fit. Generally a flat affect with little emotion shown. Strawberry blonde pixie cut, grey-blue eyes, and freckled skin.
Anatoly Fedoriw - Ella&amp;rsquo;s mentor for her graduate program.
Charlotte &amp;ldquo;Charlie&amp;rdquo; Harris - Ella&amp;rsquo;s best friend and fellow first-year Physics masters student, but is partying a bit too much since her move up from University of Georgia. From a rich Southern heritage in Savannah of the sort that has debutante balls (which she ditched out of to get drunk and have sex with her boyfriend in her parents car)</description></item><item><title>Species</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</guid><description>Ascended - Ascended are individuals how met an unknown threshold and now exist on other planes of existance. When they manifest on middle planes, they will often exhibit sensory aberrations because of their partial presence and power leakage from the other plane.
Dwarves - Dwarven males are 120 to 140cm (4' to 4'6) and females are average 5cm taller. They both appear to be roughly chiseled out of stone and rock. Their matrilineal clans are organized by rough colorations althrough intermarriage is common.</description></item></channel></rss>