<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/</link><description>Recent content on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="https://tknx.github.io/">Tarun Nagpal&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:00:41 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thethousandkingdoms.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01.010 Prep</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.010-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:00:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.010-prep/</guid><description>12 October 2021 - Jackson Heights, Queens, United States Her parents came by to bring her home later that day to take her home. They had brought their car with them to bring her home, the sacrifice of their street parking spot a true sign of love. Her mom still had the shawl wrapped around her which made Ella feel pretty warm inside.
She went into her cozy bedroom that had been split out of a larger bedroom for her and her brother.</description></item><item><title>01.009 Exposition</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.009-exposition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 13:34:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.009-exposition/</guid><description>11 October 2021 - NYU Langone Hospital, New York City, United States Ella awoke from vivid dreams of strange snake-like creatures with glowing crystalline eyes crawling up her body while she lay trapped under a giant slice of pizza.
She attributed this to the pain meds and being hungry rather than prophecy. How strange her life had become that this was the first thing that came to her.
When she looked up, she almost screamed when she saw a tall thin cadaverous looking man with pale skin, sunken dark eyes, and stringy hair sitting in the hospital room chair.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude - The Wolves of Kennington</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>10 October 2021 - Mayfair, London, United States “Ballies on, ballers tall, balls deep.”
Right fucking poet Skitz was. Thought he and our “gang” were the next Spartans to come out of Kenny but that was just stupid. Plus he couldn’t verse for shit.
I pulled down my mask and checked my ching at my side. “Skitz, you gonna duss moment we pound that door.”
“Shut up you patty. Your name gonna be Powda since you white like cake.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude Kennington</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>This chapter I am always going to say was super hard.
First, I was trying to write a character I can&amp;rsquo;t even say I pretend to understand, a council estates kid in Kennington, London from Brixton. So I am going to completely fuck up the vernacular and regional differences. He is teamed up with a native East Londoner from Kennington and a Brazilian Portuguese girl and they run into a couple Haitian pretwo lwa.
Second, I wanted it to be very in media res, but given how fast things go south, I had to move a bunch of stuff up front.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.007-again/</guid><description>This chapter was more difficult to write than the others - lots of establishing new characters and trying to imply familial relationships but with a hopefully light touch. Maybe I crammed too many conversations in here and didn&amp;rsquo;t let each one breathe, but it is a trade-off between endless dialog and moving things along, and in this story, it was just a bit of a breather.
Next chapter will be radically different.
Also, Ella switching between her American name and Indian name is very intentional.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.007-again/</guid><description>10 October 2021 - NYU Langone Hospital, New York City, United States “Motherfucker!” Ella shot out of the bed to sit straight up. And then promptly lay back down as her side screamed.
“Dhee, where did you learn such language?” Her mothers voice, and of course the first thing she said was to nag her, and Eesha had just been stabbed… for the second time.
Her mother continued reaching over to adjust the sheets. The anodyne beeping of the heart eater monitor and IV cables pretty much gave away the show.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>This was all Ella needing to feel real, and I did not expect it when I wrote it. She kind of skipped from denial to the end. Was it truly acceptance or was it her just going a bit more wild? I kind of thought of her as a third date kind of girl, but sometimes your own characters surprise you.
And then, of course, she got stabbed.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>9 October 2021 - Bushwick, Brooklyn, United States Ella thought about last night as she pulled on her top. The awkward silence at dinner. Then walking back by his apartment on her way home. Standing across from each other at the entrance.
Grabbing him and kissing him deeply right there. The scrambled wait for the elevator and laughing when some people spilled out and they got in.
Getting undressed and him demurring when she made to pull off that ring.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>After the disappointment Ella experienced in her last chapter, I felt like I needed to kickstart the story with more evidence and someone else who maybe knows a little bit more than her. Most YA stories start with the parents dying so nobody can protect or explain what is going on - and the slow reveal is important to build this. But you can be slow, and you can be glacial.
So Jae-Young shows up. A guy who asked her out early on but they only got around to a date now.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>8 October 2021 - West Village, New York City, United States The following day was a slow burn. She taught her class, graded a ton of terrible exams, and then was supposed to go out. For once it wasn’t with Charlie, but she had a date. A film grad student had asked her out a while ago, after meeting her through Jade, and they were finally getting to it… he was a cute, lanky guy named Jae-Young, or Jonny as he went by.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>Ella is very good at denial but the cracks are showing. She puts back on the denial at the end but how much longer can it last.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>7 October 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States After a sleepless night, Ella felt like she was going through the motions. She went to class, spent some time doing math for her grad work, ate food without noticing what she was eating. Her fellow doctorate students all noticed it but figured she was just hungover and that assessment was reinforced when she excused herself in the afternoon.
Ella actually had determined she would go back to the castle to get answers.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>I encourage you to channel some Sailor Moon magical girl sequencing here. Get your mind out of the gutter though - no semi-nude intermediate step.
Footnotes are purely optional and just for fun. Being much older, I will have to work on making my music choices more age appropriate, but I figured an orc DJ can be any age.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>6 October 2021 - Harlem, New York City, United States In the stairwell, Ella’s eyes were glowing brilliant white, and despite the utter darkness, she climbed the stairs gracefully up two floors in a serene daze. As she crossed each flight, she didn’t notice how her jeans and tunic shirt seemed to shift, into a trailing dress with long velvet gloves, nor, cresting the third floor, did she notice the band of light that framed circled her head hinting at a tiara.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>Yes it is a bit of a skip ahead, but often I find that the pacing of stories feels unrealistic. Also a month of having crystalline white eyes and putting in contacts to cover them makes it feel more real that she is back to living her life for the most part.
And then you get ambushed by a party. A magical dance party in Harlem on your way up town. Charlie doesn&amp;rsquo;t get past the red rope of magic.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>6 October 2021 - Harlem, New York City, United States “Why do I have to go uptown to study anyway? I know we are just going up there so you can flirt with your boyfriend.” Ella whined a bit on the A train as it pulled away from the station.
“Shut up… it isn’t that big of a deal and I like to get out of the Village sometimes for a change, you know. Plus it is Thursday night and we can go out afterwards.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/01.001-vision/</guid><description>A quick intro Well here we go&amp;hellip; I wanted to include some chapter by chapter commentary as I write these, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want unnecessary author&amp;rsquo;s notes, nor did I want them to be attached to the chapters directly. Think of this as the purely optional director&amp;rsquo;s track.
And, to be fair, I will spoil the chapters as I see fit, so read those first.
When I started this story, I had a couple goals in mind.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.001-vision/</guid><description>9 September 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States “Don’t go down there.”
Charlie looked over and smiled. “I hear there are secret tunnels and strange stuff. Let’s do this!”
She held up her phone showing a picture of something. It was hard to follow as her hand wasn’t steady and she was stumbling a bit anyway.
“They aren’t yellow bricks, but let’s go!” Charlie prompted that by climbing down off the platform, her short sparkly, clubbing dress riding up as she slide down the side</description></item><item><title>Dramatis Personae</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/dramatis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/dramatis/</guid><description>Humans Charlotte &amp;ldquo;Charlie&amp;rdquo; Harris - Ella&amp;rsquo;s best friend and fellow first-year Physics masters student, but is partying a bit too much since her move up from University of Georgia. From a rich Southern heritage in Savannah of the sort that has debutante balls (which she ditched out of to get drunk and have sex with her boyfriend in her parents car)
Eesha Eleanor Jindal-Witten - Our heroine is 5'6&amp;quot; with bronze skin from her half-Indian heritage.</description></item><item><title>Species</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</guid><description>Ascended - Ascended are individuals how met an unknown threshold and now exist on other planes of existance. When they manifest on middle planes, they will often exhibit sensory aberrations because of their partial presence and power leakage from the other plane.
Dwarves - Dwarven males are 120 to 140cm (4' to 4'6) and females are average 5cm taller. They both appear to be roughly chiseled out of stone and rock. Their matrilineal clans are organized by rough colorations althrough intermarriage is common.</description></item></channel></rss>