<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/</link><description>Recent content on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="https://tknx.github.io/">Tarun Nagpal&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:54 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thethousandkingdoms.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fedoriw, Anatoly</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/fedoriw_anatoly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/fedoriw_anatoly/</guid><description>Ella’s mentor for her graduate program.</description></item><item><title>Harris, Charlotte 'Charlie'</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/harris_charlotte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/harris_charlotte/</guid><description>Relationships Mother Melissa Harris Cousin Astor Harris Ella’s best friend and fellow first-year Physics masters student, but is partying a bit too much since her move up from University of Georgia. From a rich Southern heritage in Savannah of the sort that has debutante balls (which she ditched out of to get drunk and have sex with her boyfriend in her parents car)</description></item><item><title>Adrahasis</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/adrahasis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/adrahasis/</guid><description>Adrahasis is the unofficial leader of the cohort and is considered a bit of a philosopher warrior of the group. He has a strong grasp of strategy but is not the strongest at tactics and on the ground decisions.</description></item><item><title>Aoife</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/fae/aoife/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/fae/aoife/</guid><description>158cm / 5'2&amp;quot; petite with golden skin, blue butterfly wings. Ella was almost seduced by her during a party.</description></item><item><title>Arcsa</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/arcsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/arcsa/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Arthurs, Donna</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/arthurs_donna/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/arthurs_donna/</guid><description>Ella’s sparring partner. Very tall at 177cm / 5'10&amp;quot; and fit. Generally a flat affect with little emotion shown. Strawberry blonde pixie cut, grey-blue eyes, and freckled skin.</description></item><item><title>Bahu</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/bahu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/bahu/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Davcina</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/davcina/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/davcina/</guid><description>Davcina is tall and handsome with stern features. Her eyes were a storm at sea blue-grey, and she had high sharp cheekbones.
She is very angular looking and has a severe face but is actually very sweet and compassionate. Likes hugs type of person.</description></item><item><title>Ekerri</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/orcs/ekerri/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/orcs/ekerri/</guid><description>Strange monarch who crowned Elli. Obsidian skin and glowing white crystalline eyes</description></item><item><title>Etana</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/etana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/etana/</guid><description>Etana is long and lean with dark long hair in long braids with beads woven into the ends of them.
He is very attractive but has a raspy voice from a training incident where he got punched in the throat.
Personality is shy and withdrawn generally.</description></item><item><title>High Priestess f.k.a. Belatsunat</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/high-priestess/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/high-priestess/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Kothin</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/dwarves/kothin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/dwarves/kothin/</guid><description>The first dwarf that Ella has met. Long beard, 121cm / 4&amp;rsquo; tall. Faceted inhuman features with solid black eyes.</description></item><item><title>Ndereba, Jade</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/ndereba_jade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/ndereba_jade/</guid><description>Relationships Brother Craig Ndereba Roommate Ella Jindal-Witten Ella’s studio roommate from Kenya, tall 172m / 5'8&amp;quot; with dark black skin and leaning way into a 1970s style including massive afro. Taking a masters in Film &amp;amp; Television at NYU. A bit conceited as she used to model across Africa, but struggling with not being top of the heap in NYC.</description></item><item><title>Park, Do-Yun</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/park_do-yun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/park_do-yun/</guid><description> Relationships Spouse Johanna Son Hanuel Park Great-grandson Jae-Young Park</description></item><item><title>Park, Hanuel</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/park_hanuel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/park_hanuel/</guid><description> Relationships Father Do-Yun Park Mother Johanna Grandson Jae-Young Park</description></item><item><title>Park, Jae-Young</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/elves/park_jae-young/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/elves/park_jae-young/</guid><description>Relationships Great-grandfather Do-Yun Park Great-grandmother Johanna Grandfather Hanuel Park Ex-girlfriend Ella Jindal-Witten Ella’s ex-boyfriend. In human guise, he is 180cm / 5'11&amp;quot; tall and handsome with sharp cheekbones and a boyish haircut. Without his ring, his elfin features come to the fore, his eyes cant to an extreme degree, his features become even more defined and sharper, his ears pointed.</description></item><item><title>Slattery, Harlan</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/slattery_harlan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/slattery_harlan/</guid><description>Relationships Brother Luke Slattery Luke&amp;rsquo;s identical twin - no beard. From Texas.</description></item><item><title>Tauthe</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/tauthe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 08:19:20 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/aqrabuamelu/tauthe/</guid><description>Tauthe is a bit shorter and rounder than the other Aqrabuamelu. She is the opposite of Davcina in that she has a round open face but is a bit caustic.</description></item><item><title>Jindal-Witten, Eesha 'Eleanor'/'Ella'</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_ella/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 14:56:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_ella/</guid><description>Relationships Father Henry Jindal-Witten Mother Navneet Jindal-Witten Brother Harish &amp;ldquo;Harry&amp;rdquo; Jindal-Witten Ex-boyfriend Jae-Young Park Roommate Jade Ndereba Our heroine is 167cm / 5'6&amp;quot; with bronze skin from her half-Indian heritage. Brown eyes naturally and black hair. She starts the story at 25 years old and first-year Physics Ph.D student at NYU.</description></item><item><title>Jindal-Witten, Harish 'Harry'</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_harish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 14:56:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_harish/</guid><description>Relationships Father Henry Jindal-Witten Mother Navneet Jindal-Witten Sister Eesha Jindal-Witten The annoying little brother. Senior at Francis Lewis High School in Queens.</description></item><item><title>Jindal-Witten, Henry</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_henry/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 14:56:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_henry/</guid><description>Relationships Spouse Navneet Jindal-Witten Son Harish Jindal-Witten Daughter Eesha Jindal-Witten Ella’s father. Tall (188cm / 6'2&amp;quot;), broad shouldered, a light dusting of freckles, blue-green eyes, and tousled brown hair. Basically a very handsome guy with a square jaw. Was a soap opera actor, minor love interest in several movies before going back to school and eventually become a professor of anthropology.</description></item><item><title>Jindal-Witten, Navneet</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_navneet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 14:56:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/dramatis/humans/jindal-witten_navneet/</guid><description>Relationships Spouse Henry Jindal-Witten Son Harish Jindal-Witten Daughter Eesha Jindal-Witten Ella&amp;rsquo;s mother. Short (160cm / 5'4&amp;quot;), petite and perhaps more attractive than her husband. If undercut by her knowing it. Always super-fashionable and put together, she is the kind of person who would put on makeup before the apocalypse and take time to adjust it during.Trauma surgeon at New York Presbytarian in Queens.</description></item><item><title>01.029 Home</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.029-home/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 20:20:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.029-home/</guid><description>Friday, December 31, 2021 - Reykjavik, Iceland &amp;ldquo;Are you really going to do it?&amp;rdquo; Jae-Young asked her anxiously. He was fidgeting with the ring on his finger.
&amp;ldquo;Are we really going to talk about this again? Yes.&amp;rdquo; Ella said. She understood his concern, but part of her wanted to tell him he gave up that right to be possessive when they had broken up. But she knew that was unfair and he was just concerned.</description></item><item><title>01.028 Rainment</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.028-rainment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 20:20:46 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.028-rainment/</guid><description>Thursday, December 30, 2021 - The Kingdom of the Huldufólk The vanilla custard and almond filling had made her fingers sticky and she looked around the room before just getting up and going to the bathroom sink to wash them off.
She came back and looked disconsolately at the remains of the pastry she had eaten. The pastry Jae-Young had brought back from town. Damn him for breaking up with her so nicely. And then feeding her?</description></item><item><title>01.027 Break</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.027-break/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 20:20:39 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.027-break/</guid><description>Thursday, December 30, 2021 - The Hidden Kingdom of the Huldufólk &amp;ldquo;Look, look,&amp;rdquo; Ella said excitedly, meanwhile, her finger was glowing steadily leaving trails in the air that hung for a moment and dissolved into glittery dust.
Reynard regarded her with wide eyes, &amp;ldquo;How much have you been practicing?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Hmm.&amp;rdquo; She started counting fingers on her other hand using her glowing finger, &amp;ldquo;I get up and go for a run, then shower and breakfast, then practice for three hours&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; she went through the past few days, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; about ten hours a day for the past five days.</description></item><item><title>01.026 Bless Your Heart</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.026-blessyourheart/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 17:50:28 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.026-blessyourheart/</guid><description>Christmas, Saturday 25 December 2021 - Savannah, Georgia, United States Charlie sat glumly on the chaise. Her mother was puttering around adding tinsel to the very oversized Christmas tree before the rest of the family came over and talking about how it was finally perfect. As if she hadn&amp;rsquo;t paid some very expensive professionals to bring in and decorate the tree
Charlie was digging around her purse when she had a happy bit of circumstance happen and she surreptitiously pulled out two forgotten tabs of molly that were sitting in the bottom.</description></item><item><title>01.025 Merry Christmas</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.025-merrychristmas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:55:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.025-merrychristmas/</guid><description>Friday, December 24, 2021 - Near Húsavík, Iceland &amp;ldquo;So anyway. Are you liking it here? Aren&amp;rsquo;t elves the coolest? You know I was an orphan right? My parents died when I was tiny, fell right down a glacier crevice and were never seen again! And the elves found me wandering near the camp and took me in. And look at me now, it is like a huge family of immortal fairy creatures! And they have so few children they just have no idea what to do with me.</description></item><item><title>01.024 Sitdown</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.024-sitdown/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:55:22 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.024-sitdown/</guid><description>Thursday, December 23, 2021 - Near Húsavík, Iceland The both of them followed Jóhanna as she led them down a corridor silently. She walked elegantly, almost floating, but somehow managed to maintain a quick pace.
They entered another room, Jóhanna ducking through the short doorway, and found their bags were already there. It was a small sitting room, like a hotel suite.
&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s sit here&amp;rdquo; and she promptly sat down and gestured to the other two chairs.</description></item><item><title>01.023 Huldufólk</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.023-huldufolk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:55:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.023-huldufolk/</guid><description>Wednesday, December 22, 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States Ella looked over her packed bags one more time. She had stripped down and packed them several times to maximize what would carry her the furthest. Waterproofed cold weather hiking boots. Lots of technical and technicolor clothing she had scrounged from friends.
She threw in some notebooks and other random items and called it good.
Jade had already left for the holiday with her brother Craig and a large group who were all going to New Hampshire for skiing.</description></item><item><title>01.022 Coffee</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.022-coffee/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:55:16 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.022-coffee/</guid><description>Friday, December 17, 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States &amp;ldquo;So I was thinking, the people of Iceland are big into these legends of elves. They think they live in rocks in lava fields and other areas like that.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Right&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; said Ella as she paged through Jae-Young&amp;rsquo;s notes.
&amp;ldquo;Well&amp;hellip; we aren&amp;rsquo;t going to be finding cosmopolitan elves hanging around in Reykjavik and running coffee shops and whatever.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Why not? I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have expected one to be a film grad student in New York either!</description></item><item><title>01.021 Reset</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.021-reset/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:55:12 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.021-reset/</guid><description>Sunday, November 28, 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States Ella lay in bed. The sunlight peeked through the drawn curtains and denied her sleep. She was tired after staying up the whole night but her mind kept racing through what she had heard.
She pulled her phone out and started to write notes on it all. And seeing it in print left very few choices.
She typed on her phone quickly and then slowed down as the conclusion became inevitable:</description></item><item><title>01.020 History</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.020-history/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 13:26:29 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.020-history/</guid><description>Sunday, November 28, 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States &amp;ldquo;Hey lover&amp;hellip; this an early morning booty call?.&amp;rdquo; Ella was relaxed and a bit punchy from staying up all night.
&amp;ldquo;Excuse me?&amp;rdquo; The voice was unfamiliar and Ella quickly looked at her phone. It was a group call.
&amp;ldquo;Ummm&amp;hellip;. Ella, this is my grandfather.&amp;rdquo; Jae-Young&amp;rsquo;s voice broke in. Ella could feel the flush in her face, and she stammered a bit before a greeting.</description></item><item><title>01.019 Anxiety</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.019-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 13:26:26 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.019-anxiety/</guid><description>Saturday, November 27, 2021 - Irvington, New Jersey, United States &amp;ldquo;That was awful. Just awful. In all my days teaching, I have never seen anyone worse. Here, you see this?&amp;rdquo; The instructor was pointing to a small origami person he had been folding while Ella had run the course, &amp;ldquo;I could tape a gun to this and it would have been a better run.&amp;rdquo;
Ella just nodded and trembled a bit. She didn&amp;rsquo;t say anything.</description></item><item><title>01.018 Farflung Interests</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.018-farflung/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 13:26:23 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.018-farflung/</guid><description>Saturday, November 27, 2021 - Atacama, Chile &amp;ldquo;Bring the find here,&amp;rdquo; Kothin yelled down the tunnel.
&amp;ldquo;¿Que ?&amp;rdquo; came a voice across the field .
Kothin cursed a bit and then pulled out his phone. After a bit of typing, &amp;ldquo;¡Tráelo aquí!&amp;rdquo;
The workers worked their way over, sloshing right through the intervening brine pool.
&amp;ldquo;Dámelo&amp;rdquo; he said perfunctorily. The workers handed over the lithium slurry. Kothin could feel the mineral composition and after a lot of cursing, references to the translation app, and hand gestures indicated the processing that still needed to take place.</description></item><item><title>01.017 Aqrabuamelu</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.017-aqrabuamelu/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:19:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.017-aqrabuamelu/</guid><description>Ṭebētu, 14 Nabopolassar (January 1, 2921 BCE) - The Hidden Kingdom of Akkad Arcsa tried to lick his dry lips but even his tongue was dry. When Marat had come, he had thought she would perhaps take part of his ration. But he must have looked too weak, and she would not leave any if he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t survive for her to take his next water ration. So she had taken it all. He had fallen so far from grace.</description></item><item><title>01.016 Blooded</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.016-blooded/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:19:37 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.016-blooded/</guid><description>Thanksgiving, November 25, 2021 - Jackson Heights, Queens, United States &amp;ldquo;Stop swearing at once!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Alright mom. Now let me and my friends play.&amp;rdquo; Harish&amp;rsquo;s voice was a bit whiny sounding.
&amp;ldquo;I should throw that thing out the door.&amp;rdquo;
Harish kept grumbling while closing the door which intensified when Ella coming around her mother stuck her foot in the way before coming in.
&amp;ldquo;Whatcha doin&amp;rsquo;?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;What do you think I am doing? Playing games with my fam.</description></item><item><title>01.015 Investigation</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.015-investigation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:19:17 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.015-investigation/</guid><description>Monday, November 22, 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York, United States Ella felt she was suspicious as she creeped around the Applied Physics lab. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that much of a stretch for her to be here since she was a physicist, but knowing she wanted to use the equipment for non-Ph.D related analysis made her nervous. The professors and students just ignored her.
Eventually she found someone at the door to the room of the SEM.</description></item><item><title>01.014 Punked</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.014-punked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:19:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.014-punked/</guid><description>Saturday, November 20, 2021 - Chinatown, New York City, United States Ella fell back. The leg catch and sweep knocking her down.
&amp;ldquo;Damn it.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Get up.&amp;rdquo; Donna&amp;rsquo;s voice was flat. Almost bored sounding. As opposed to the endless punk music screeching from the radio.
They had been here for hours. Donna seemed to take delight in knocking her over. They were mostly sticking to striking since they were in a Muay Thai gym but Donna didn&amp;rsquo;t have problems throwing in hooking moves and other illegal moves.</description></item><item><title>01.013 Sparring</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.013-sparring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:55:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.013-sparring/</guid><description>Now you see the true power of Ella’s very mild enhanced healing. Since this is a rational, progression story with an entirely optional litrpg backbone, I wanted to have a bit of slice of life period showing that she is intensely following up on her action items. So this is part of the training montage for hand-to-hand.
Since I know about fighting than physics expect me to spend more time on those scenes rather than her studying.</description></item><item><title>01.013 Sparring</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.013-sparring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:55:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.013-sparring/</guid><description>Thursday, 18 November 2021 - Long Island City, Queens, United States &amp;ldquo;Ah shit!&amp;rdquo;
Ell landed on her butt. Breathing hard. Craig stood over her.
&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have ever seen anyone improve as quickly as you. You come in every day, work on things until you are collapsing on the ground. You chill out a bit, drink a sports drink, get on the weights and bump up your weight hard for your size. Then you come in the next day bouncy as a bunny with no soreness.</description></item><item><title>01.012 Halloween</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.012-halloween/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.012-halloween/</guid><description>A bit more training montage, but I wanted to bring back in some magic and even a sense of wonder. I feel like I missed the mark a bit. But that is okay.
I am not a hard magic guy for the most part despite some of my rpg type posts - my eyes glaze over at most hard magic systems, so I prefer it to be a bit ineffable.
That will get harder as we get to learning more about magic, I want to have the system underneath to keep it somewhat real, but to the reader it needs to feel like, well, magic.</description></item><item><title>01.012 Halloween</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.012-halloween/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.012-halloween/</guid><description>October 31, 2021 - Long Island City, Queens, United States &amp;ldquo;Hands up!&amp;rdquo; And Craig followed with a flick jab and a &amp;ldquo;gentle&amp;rdquo; body blow.
&amp;ldquo;Ufff&amp;rdquo; Ella completely lost her breath and landed on her ass.
&amp;ldquo;You are strong for your size. And your reflexes are on fire. You also don&amp;rsquo;t make the same mistake twice.&amp;rdquo; He looked at her sitting on the ground, &amp;ldquo;well three times anyway.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Three things for you to work on: You aren&amp;rsquo;t keeping your core tight enough when you strike or defend.</description></item><item><title>01.011 Breathe</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.011-breathe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:01:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.011-breathe/</guid><description>I was going for that calm before the storm vibe here, she is mentally getting her head into the game a bit. Taking stock. Taking time with her family.
I&amp;rsquo;ll probably come back and build this out when I do a big second pass to build on that feel more. But sometimes a chapter is just short.</description></item><item><title>01.011 Breathe</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.011-breathe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:01:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.011-breathe/</guid><description>October 13, 2021 - Jackson Heights, Queens, United States The following day, she came down in her pajamas after waking up way too early, stretching and yawning. Her brother was already wolfing down cereal with headphones in, head bobbing along to something.
She made her way over, got a bowl of cereal of her own and snagged the milk out of Harish&amp;rsquo;s grasp before he could drink it all.
Heading back up to her room, she started thinking about her final issue which was really the long pole, what was going on and how could she prepare for it better.</description></item><item><title>01.010 Prep</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.010-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:00:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.010-prep/</guid><description>Dealing with one&amp;rsquo;s parents is often something that is brushed over in fantasy. You can&amp;rsquo;t have adventures with watchful parents. I somewhat get around this by having my protagonist be older, in grad school. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean she is estranged from her family, just exasperated sometimes.
Her father being an actor once and now a professor and her mother being a physician is intentional. She comes from an educated background but not one that is solely that way.</description></item><item><title>01.010 Prep</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.010-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:00:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.010-prep/</guid><description>October 12, 2021 - Jackson Heights, Queens, United States Her parents came by to bring her home later that day to take her home. They had brought their car with them to bring her home, the sacrifice of their street parking spot a true sign of love. Her mom still had the shawl wrapped around her which made Ella feel pretty warm inside.
She went into her cozy bedroom that had been split out of a larger bedroom for her and her brother.</description></item><item><title>01.009 Exposition</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.009-exposition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 13:34:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.009-exposition/</guid><description>Who knew that dwarves were trolls? Sorry I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself.
Obviously I wanted to subvert the trope a bit that dwarves were either fools like in LOTR or stoic. At the same time, I also added my own spin on them, making them rock-like creatures that are a bit more alien in nature than humans.
There is always a bit of give and take with that since you have to balance their alieness with their ability to interact in a meaningful way with humans.</description></item><item><title>01.009 Exposition</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.009-exposition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 13:34:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.009-exposition/</guid><description>October 11, 2021 - NYU Langone Hospital, New York City, United States Ella awoke from vivid dreams of strange snake-like creatures with glowing crystalline eyes crawling up her body while she lay trapped under a giant slice of pizza.
She attributed this to the pain meds and being hungry rather than prophecy. How strange her life had become that this was the first thing that came to her.
When she looked up, she almost screamed when she saw a tall thin cadaverous looking man with pale skin, sunken dark eyes, and stringy hair sitting in the hospital room chair.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude - The Wolves of Kennington</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>October 10, 2021 - Mayfair, London, United Kingdom &amp;ldquo;Ballies on, ballers tall, balls deep.&amp;rdquo;
Right fucking poet Skitz was. Thought he and our &amp;ldquo;gang&amp;rdquo; were the next Spartans to come out of Kenny but that was just stupid. Plus he couldn&amp;rsquo;t verse for shit.
I pulled down my mask and checked my ching at my side. &amp;ldquo;Skitz, you gonna duss moment we pound that door.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Shut up you patty. Your name gonna be Powda since you white like cake.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude Kennington</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>This chapter I am always going to say was super hard.
First, I was trying to write a character I can&amp;rsquo;t even say I pretend to understand, a council estates kid in Kennington, London from Brixton. So I am going to completely fuck up the vernacular and regional differences. He is teamed up with a native East Londoner from Kennington and a Brazilian Portuguese girl and they run into a couple Haitian pretwo lwa.
Second, I wanted it to be very in media res, but given how fast things go south, I had to move a bunch of stuff up front.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.007-again/</guid><description>This chapter was more difficult to write than the others - lots of establishing new characters and trying to imply familial relationships but with a hopefully light touch. Maybe I crammed too many conversations in here and didn&amp;rsquo;t let each one breathe, but it is a trade-off between endless dialog and moving things along, and in this story, it was just a bit of a breather.
Next chapter will be radically different.
Also, Ella switching between her American name and Indian name is very intentional.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.007-again/</guid><description>October 10, 2021 - NYU Langone Hospital, New York City, United States &amp;ldquo;Motherfucker!&amp;rdquo; Ella shot out of the bed to sit straight up. And then promptly lay back down as her side screamed.
&amp;ldquo;Dhee, where did you learn such language?&amp;rdquo; Her mothers voice, and of course the first thing she said was to nag her, and Eesha had just been stabbed&amp;hellip; for the second time.
Her mother continued reaching over to adjust the sheets. The anodyne beeping of the vital signs monitor and IV cables pretty much gave away the show.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>This was all Ella needing to feel real, and I did not expect it when I wrote it. A lot of the time characters pull you along with their own actions, and you just let them.
She kind of skipped from denial to the end. Was it truly acceptance or was it her just going a bit more wild? I kind of thought of her as a third date kind of girl, but sometimes your own characters surprise you.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>October 9, 2021 - Bushwick, Brooklyn, United States Ella thought about last night as she pulled on her top. The awkward silence at dinner. Then walking back by his apartment on her way home. Standing across from each other at the entrance.
Grabbing him and kissing him deeply right there. The scrambled wait for the elevator and laughing when some people spilled out and they got in.
Getting undressed and him demurring when she made to pull off that ring.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>After the disappointment Ella experienced in her last chapter, I felt like I needed to kickstart the story with more evidence and someone else who maybe knows a little bit more than her. Most YA stories start with the parents dying so nobody can protect or explain what is going on - and the slow reveal is important to build this. But you can be slow, and you can be glacial.
So Jae-Young shows up. A guy who asked her out early on but they only got around to a date now.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>October 8, 2021 - West Village, New York City, United States The following day was a slow burn. She taught her class, graded a ton of terrible exams, and then was supposed to go out. For once it wasn&amp;rsquo;t with Charlie, but she had a date. A film grad student had asked her out a while ago, after meeting her through Jade, and they were finally getting to it&amp;hellip; he was a cute, lanky guy named Jae-Young, or Johnny as he went by.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>Ella is very good at denial but the cracks are showing. She puts back on the denial at the end but how much longer can it last.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>October 7, 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States After a sleepless night, Ella felt like she was going through the motions. She went to class, spent some time doing math for her grad work, and ate food without noticing what she was eating. Her fellow doctorate students all noticed it but figured she was just hungover and that assessment was reinforced when she excused herself in the afternoon.
Ella actually had determined she would go back to the castle to get answers.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>I encourage you to channel some Sailor Moon magical girl sequencing here. Get your mind out of the gutter though - no semi-nude intermediate step.
Footnotes are purely optional and just for fun. Being much older, I will have to work on making my music choices more age appropriate, but I figured an orc DJ can be any age.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>October 6, 2021 - Harlem, New York City, United States In the stairwell, Ella&amp;rsquo;s eyes were glowing brilliant white, and &amp;mdash; despite the utter darkness &amp;mdash; she climbed the stairs gracefully up two floors in a serene daze. As she crossed each flight, she didn&amp;rsquo;t notice how her jeans and tunic shirt seemed to shift, into a trailing dress with long velvet gloves, nor, her mask fading away. And then cresting the third floor, a band of light that framed circled her head hinting at a tiara started to form.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>Yes it is a bit of a skip ahead, but often I find that the pacing of stories feels unrealistic. Also a month of having crystalline white eyes and putting in contacts to cover them makes it feel more real that she is back to living her life for the most part.
And then you get ambushed by a party. A magical dance party in Harlem on your way up town. Charlie doesn&amp;rsquo;t get past the red rope of magic.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>October 6, 2021 - Harlem, New York City, United States &amp;ldquo;Why do I have to go uptown to study anyway? I know we are just going up there so you can flirt with your boyfriend.&amp;rdquo; Ella whined a bit on the A train as it pulled away from the station.
&amp;ldquo;Shut up&amp;hellip; it isn&amp;rsquo;t that big of a deal and I like to get out of the Village sometimes for a change, you know. Plus it is Thursday night and we can go out afterwards.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/commentary/vol01/01.001-vision/</guid><description>A quick intro Well here we go&amp;hellip; I wanted to include some chapter by chapter commentary as I write these, but didn&amp;rsquo;t want unnecessary author&amp;rsquo;s notes, nor did I want them to be attached to the chapters directly. Think of this as the purely optional director&amp;rsquo;s track.
And, to be fair, I will spoil the chapters as I see fit, so read those first.
When I started this story, I had a couple goals in mind.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/01.001-vision/</guid><description>September 9, 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t go down there.&amp;rdquo;
Charlie looked over and smiled. &amp;ldquo;I hear there are secret tunnels and strange stuff. Let&amp;rsquo;s do this!&amp;rdquo;
She held up her phone showing a picture of something. It was hard to follow as her hand wasn&amp;rsquo;t steady, and Charlie was stumbling a bit anyway.
&amp;ldquo;These aren&amp;rsquo;t yellow bricks, but let&amp;rsquo;s go!&amp;rdquo; Charlie prompted that by jumping down from the platform, her short sparkly, clubbing skirt flaring up as she somehow didn&amp;rsquo;t break the heels she was in.</description></item><item><title>Species</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</guid><description>Ascended - Ascended are individuals how met an unknown threshold and now exist on other planes of existance. When they manifest on middle planes, they will often exhibit sensory aberrations because of their partial presence and power leakage from the other plane.
Dwarves - Dwarven males are 120 to 140cm (4&amp;rsquo; to 4'6) and females are average 5cm taller. They both appear to be roughly chiseled out of stone and rock. Their matrilineal clans are organized by rough colorations althrough intermarriage is common.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/maybe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/vol01/maybe/</guid><description>Jade came into the room and yelled out, &amp;ldquo;Turn on the news. More weird shit is going on.&amp;rdquo;
She quickly hopped onto her laptop and pulled up the BBC.
&amp;ldquo;What the fuck?&amp;rdquo; Ella whispered.
Jade yelled across the curtain that separate the room. &amp;ldquo;It just showed up about forty five minutes ago. People are freaking out!&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Large orbital mass outside lunar orbit detected&amp;hellip; Orbiting Earth&amp;hellip; satellites being pulled off their trajectories?&amp;rdquo; Ella read through the article quickly.</description></item></channel></rss>