<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/</link><description>Recent content on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="https://tknx.github.io/">Tarun Nagpal&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thethousandkingdoms.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>0.1.5 The Date</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.5-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.5-the-date/</guid><description>The following day was a slow burn. She taught her class, graded a ton of terrible exams, and then was supposed to go out. For once it wasn’t with Charlie, but she had a date. A film grad student had asked her out over a while ago and they were finally getting to it… he was a cute, lanky guy named Jae-Young, or Jonny as he went by. Even though Ella didn’t use her Indian name, she figured she would start with Jae-Young and see if he corrected her.</description></item><item><title>0.1.4 You Cant Go Back</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.4-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.4-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>After a sleepless night, Ella felt like she was going through the motions. She went to class, spent some time doing math for her grad work, ate food without noticing what she was eating. Her fellow doctorate students all noticed it but figured she was just hungover and that assessment was reinforced when she excused herself in the afternoon.
Ella actually had determined she would go back to the castle to get answers. Something had happened there, and, in an extreme act of denial, she had avoided thinking about it until last night had brought it back into focus.</description></item><item><title>0.1.3 The Party</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.3-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.3-the-party/</guid><description>In the stairwell, Ella’s eyes were glowing brilliant white, and despite the utter darkness, she climbed the stairs gracefully up two floors in a serene daze. As she crossed each flight, she didn’t notice how her jeans and tunic shirt seemed to shift, into a trailing dress with long velvet gloves, nor, cresting the third floor, did she notice the band of light that framed circled her head hinting at a tiara.
She approached an apartment door which swung open unprompted and, holding open the door, was a man with white butterfly wings and rose-gold skin and eyes, much shorter than Ella’s 5’6”, he bowed deeply.</description></item><item><title>0.1.2 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.2-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.2-one-month-later/</guid><description>“Why do I have to go uptown to study anyway? I know we are just going up there so you can flirt with your boyfriend.” Ella whined a bit on the A train as it pulled away from the station.
“Shut up… it isn’t that big of a deal and I like to get out of the Village sometimes for a change, you know. Plus it is Thursday night and we can go out afterwards. You have been a total bore lately.</description></item><item><title>0.1.1 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.1-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/0.1.1-vision/</guid><description>“Don’t go down there.”
Charlie looked over and smiled. “I hear there are secret tunnels and strange stuff. Let’s do this!”
She held up her phone showing a picture of something. It was hard to follow as her hand wasn’t steady and she was stumbling a bit anyway.
“They aren’t yellow bricks, but let’s go!” Charlie prompted that by climbing down off the platform, her short sparkly, clubbing dress riding up as she slide down the side</description></item><item><title>Dramatis Personae</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/dramatis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/dramatis/</guid><description>Eesha Vikram-</description></item><item><title>Species</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/reference/species/</guid><description>Ascended - Ascended are individuals how met an unknown threshold and now exist on other planes of existance. When they manifest on middle planes, they will often exhibit sensory aberrations because of their partial presence and power leakage from the other plane.
Dwarves - Dwarven males are 120 to 140cm (4' to 4'6) and females are average 5cm taller. They both appear to be roughly chiseled out of stone and rock. Their matrilineal clans are organized by rough colorations althrough intermarriage is common.</description></item></channel></rss>