<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Thousand Kingdoms</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content on The Thousand Kingdoms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2021 &lt;a href="https://tknx.github.io/">Tarun Nagpal&lt;/a></copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:19:33 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>01.014 Punked</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.014-punked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 15:19:33 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.014-punked/</guid><description>Saturday, 20 November 2021 - Chinatown, New York City, United States Ella fell back. The leg catch and sweep knocking her down.
“Damn it.”
“Get up.” Donna’s voice was flat. Almost bored sounding. As opposed to the endless punk music screeching from the radio.
They had been here for hours. Donna seemed to take delight in knocking her over. They were mostly sticking to striking since they were in a Muay Thai gym but Donna didn’t have problems throwing in hooking moves and other illegal moves.</description></item><item><title>01.013 Sparring</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.013-sparring/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 09:55:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.013-sparring/</guid><description>Thursday, 18 November 2021 - Long Island City, Queens, United States “Ah shit!”
Ell landed on her butt. Breathing hard. Craig stood over her.
“I don’t think I have ever seen anyone improve as quickly as you. You come in every day, work on things until you are collapsing on the ground. You chill out a bit, drink a sports drink, get on the weights and bump up your weight hard for your size. Then you come in the next day bouncy as a bunny with no soreness.</description></item><item><title>01.012 Halloween</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.012-halloween/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:58:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.012-halloween/</guid><description>31 October 2021 - Long Island City, Queens, United States “Hands up!” And Craig followed with a flick jab and a “gentle” body blow.
“Ufff” Ella completely lost her breath and landed on her ass.
“You are strong for your size. And your reflexes are on fire. You also don’t make the same mistake twice.” He looked at her sitting on the ground, “well three times anyway.”
“Three things for you to work on: You aren’t keeping your core tight enough when you strike or defend.</description></item><item><title>01.011 Breathe</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.011-breathe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 11:01:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.011-breathe/</guid><description>13 October 2021 - Jackson Heights, Queens, United States The following day, she came down in her pajamas after waking up way too early, stretching and yawning. Her brother was already wolfing down cereal with headphones in, head bobbing along to something.
She made her way over, got a bowl of cereal of her own and snagged the milk out of Harish’s grasp before he could drink it all.
Heading back up to her room, she started thinking about her final issue which was really the long pole, what was going on and how could she prepare for it better.</description></item><item><title>01.010 Prep</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.010-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 21:00:41 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.010-prep/</guid><description>12 October 2021 - Jackson Heights, Queens, United States Her parents came by to bring her home later that day to take her home. They had brought their car with them to bring her home, the sacrifice of their street parking spot a true sign of love. Her mom still had the shawl wrapped around her which made Ella feel pretty warm inside.
She went into her cozy bedroom that had been split out of a larger bedroom for her and her brother.</description></item><item><title>01.009 Exposition</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.009-exposition/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 13:34:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.009-exposition/</guid><description>11 October 2021 - NYU Langone Hospital, New York City, United States Ella awoke from vivid dreams of strange snake-like creatures with glowing crystalline eyes crawling up her body while she lay trapped under a giant slice of pizza.
She attributed this to the pain meds and being hungry rather than prophecy. How strange her life had become that this was the first thing that came to her.
When she looked up, she almost screamed when she saw a tall thin cadaverous looking man with pale skin, sunken dark eyes, and stringy hair sitting in the hospital room chair.</description></item><item><title>01.008 Interlude - The Wolves of Kennington</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.008-interlude-kennington/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 09:53:13 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.008-interlude-kennington/</guid><description>10 October 2021 - Mayfair, London, United States “Ballies on, ballers tall, balls deep.”
Right fucking poet Skitz was. Thought he and our “gang” were the next Spartans to come out of Kenny but that was just stupid. Plus he couldn’t verse for shit.
I pulled down my mask and checked my ching at my side. “Skitz, you gonna duss moment we pound that door.”
“Shut up you patty. Your name gonna be Powda since you white like cake.</description></item><item><title>01.007 Again</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.007-again/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 18:53:01 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.007-again/</guid><description>10 October 2021 - NYU Langone Hospital, New York City, United States “Motherfucker!” Ella shot out of the bed to sit straight up. And then promptly lay back down as her side screamed.
“Dhee, where did you learn such language?” Her mothers voice, and of course the first thing she said was to nag her, and Eesha had just been stabbed… for the second time.
Her mother continued reaching over to adjust the sheets. The anodyne beeping of the heart eater monitor and IV cables pretty much gave away the show.</description></item><item><title>01.006 Acceptance</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.006-acceptance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:03:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.006-acceptance/</guid><description>9 October 2021 - Bushwick, Brooklyn, United States Ella thought about last night as she pulled on her top. The awkward silence at dinner. Then walking back by his apartment on her way home. Standing across from each other at the entrance.
Grabbing him and kissing him deeply right there. The scrambled wait for the elevator and laughing when some people spilled out and they got in.
Getting undressed and him demurring when she made to pull off that ring.</description></item><item><title>01.005 The Date</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.005-the-date/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:20:40 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.005-the-date/</guid><description>8 October 2021 - West Village, New York City, United States The following day was a slow burn. She taught her class, graded a ton of terrible exams, and then was supposed to go out. For once it wasn’t with Charlie, but she had a date. A film grad student had asked her out a while ago, after meeting her through Jade, and they were finally getting to it… he was a cute, lanky guy named Jae-Young, or Jonny as he went by.</description></item><item><title>01.004 You Can't Go Back</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:11:54 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.004-you-cant-go-back/</guid><description>7 October 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States After a sleepless night, Ella felt like she was going through the motions. She went to class, spent some time doing math for her grad work, ate food without noticing what she was eating. Her fellow doctorate students all noticed it but figured she was just hungover and that assessment was reinforced when she excused herself in the afternoon.
Ella actually had determined she would go back to the castle to get answers.</description></item><item><title>01.003 The Party</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.003-the-party/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:10:31 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.003-the-party/</guid><description>6 October 2021 - Harlem, New York City, United States In the stairwell, Ella’s eyes were glowing brilliant white, and despite the utter darkness, she climbed the stairs gracefully up two floors in a serene daze. As she crossed each flight, she didn’t notice how her jeans and tunic shirt seemed to shift, into a trailing dress with long velvet gloves, nor, her mask fading away. And then cresting the third floor, a band of light that framed circled her head hinting at a tiara started to form.</description></item><item><title>01.002 One Month Later</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.002-one-month-later/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:09:10 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.002-one-month-later/</guid><description>6 October 2021 - Harlem, New York City, United States “Why do I have to go uptown to study anyway? I know we are just going up there so you can flirt with your boyfriend.” Ella whined a bit on the A train as it pulled away from the station.
“Shut up… it isn’t that big of a deal and I like to get out of the Village sometimes for a change, you know. Plus it is Thursday night and we can go out afterwards.</description></item><item><title>01.001 Vision</title><link>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.001-vision/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 18:05:48 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://thethousandkingdoms.com/posts/01.001-vision/</guid><description>9 September 2021 - Greenwich Village, New York City, United States “Don’t go down there.”
Charlie looked over and smiled. “I hear there are secret tunnels and strange stuff. Let’s do this!”
She held up her phone showing a picture of something. It was hard to follow as her hand wasn’t steady and she was stumbling a bit anyway.
“They aren’t yellow bricks, but let’s go!” Charlie prompted that by climbing down off the platform, her short sparkly, clubbing dress riding up as she slide down the side</description></item></channel></rss>